

Peng Zhao Ph.D.

+86 18782945984 pengzhao@cqmu.edu.cn

> No. 1, Yixueyuan Road, Yuzhong District, Chongqing 400016, P.R.China

Peng Zhao

Postdoctoral in basic medicine

About me I am a postdoctoral researcher in basic medicine at Chongqing Medical University. My advisor is Prof. <u>Bo Wen</u> from Fudan University. I got my Ph.D. in School of Computer Science and Technology, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC), During my doctoral study, As a visiting student, I went to indiana University School of Medicine in the United States for a year with the support of China Scholarship Council.

Research Interests

• Artificial Intelligence Theory:

Research on machine learning, deep learning methods and algorithms such as matrix decomposition, tensor decomposition, sparse representation learning, transfer learning, and Contrastive Learning.

• Bioinformatics:

Research on the application of machine learning algorithms to genetic data, epigenetic data analysis, etc. Current research work focuses on single-cell sequencing data for early detection and diagnosis of tumors.

• Intersection of medicine and engineering:

Aiming at the deep mining of medical data such as pathology images and electronic medical records, we are expanding new ways in medicalindustrial crossover accurate diagnosis to help clinical diagnosis and clinical decision-making.

Work History

2022.09 - Current

ChongQing Medical University (CQMU)

• Postdoctor in Bioinformatics (Advisor: Prof. Bo Wen)

2021.12 - 2022.06

Shenzhen Research Institute, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (SZRI)

•Intern in Computer Science (Mentor: Prof. Irwin King)

2018.11 - 2019.12

Indiana University School of Medicine (IUSM)

•Visiting Student in Machine Learning and Computational Biology (Advisor: Prof. Kun Huang)

Education

2016.09 - 2022.06

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC)

• Ph.D. in Computer Science and Technology (Advisor: Prof. Zenglin Xu) 2014.09 - 2016.06

University of Electronic Science and Technology of China (UESTC)

• M.Sc. in Electronics and Communication Engineering (MD-PHD)

2010.09 - 2014.06

Sichuan Normal University (SICNU)

• B.Sc. in Mathematics and Applied Mathematics

Publications

- 1. **Peng Zhao**, Zenglin Xu, Junjie Chen, Yazhou Ren, and Irwin King. Single Cell Self-Paced Clustering with Transcriptome Sequencing Data. International Journal of Molecular Sciences, 2022. (SCI)
- 2. **Peng Zhao**, Hongjie Wu, Shudong Huang. Multi-view Graph Clustering by Adaptive Manifold Learning[J]. Mathematics, 2022. (SCI)
- 3. **Peng Zhao**, Yongpan Sheng, Xiaohui Zhan. An advanced NMF-based approach for single cell data clustering[C]. Proceedings of 2022 2nd IEEE International Conference on Information Communication and Software Engineering, 2022.
- 4. **Peng Zhao***, Wenhua Zang*, Bin Liu, Zhao Kang, Kun Bai, Kaizhu Huang, and Zenglin Xu. Domain Adaptation with Feature and Label Adversarial Networks. Neurocomputing, 2020. (SCI)
- 5. Yazhou Ren, **Peng Zhao**, Yongpan Sheng, Dezhong Yao, and Zenglin Xu. Robust Softmax Regression for Multi-class Classification with Self-Paced Learning, In Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), 2017. (CCF A, The first author was my mentor.)
- 6. Fen Chen, **Peng Zhao**, Ting Feng Tang, and Yan Zhou . Fast Low-Rank Decomposition Model-Based Hyperspectral Image Classification Method[J]. IEEE Geoscience and Remote Sensing Letters, 2017, 14(2): 169-173. (SCI, The first author was my mentor.)
- 7. Yazhou Ren, **Peng Zhao**, Zenglin Xu, and Dezhong Yao. Balanced self-paced learning with feature corruption. In Proceedings of the International Joint Conference on Neural Networks (IJCNN) pages 2064–2071, 2017. (CCF C, The first author was my mentor.)
- 8. Shudong Huang, **Peng Zhao**, Yazhou Ren, Tianrui Li, Zenglin Xu. Self-paced and Soft-weighted NMF for Data Representation. Knowledge-Based Systems, 2019. (SCI)
- 9. Yazhou Ren, Shudong Huang, **Peng Zhao**, Zenglin Xu. Self-paced and Auto-weighted Multi-view Clustering. Neurocomputing, 2020. (SCI)
- 10. Fen Chen, Sijia Lu, **Peng Zhao**, Tim Van de Voorde, and Wenbo Xu. Urban Land Cover Mapping from Airborne Hyperspectral Imagery Using a Fast Jointly Sparse Spectral Mixture Analysis Method. Canadian Journal of Remote Sensing, 2020. (SCI)
- 11. Fangfei Lin, Bing Bai, Kun Bai, Yazhou Ren, **Peng Zhao**, Zenglin Xu. Contrastive Multi-view Hyperbolic Hierarchical Clustering. IJCAI 2022. (CCF A)
- 12. Wei Wei, Zhenting Huang, Bo Ye, Xiaoling Mu, Jing Qiao, **Peng Zhao**, Yuehang Jiang, Jingxian Wu and Xiaohui Zhan. Prediction of prognosis, immunotherapy and chemotherapy with an immunerelated risk score model in endometrial cancer. International Conference on Intelligent Biology and Medicine (ICIBM 2023).

Awards and Honors

- China Scholarship Council Scholarship, 2018
- First-class scholarship for postgraduate students in UESTC, 2017
- The second prize of China Undergraduate Mathematical Contest in Modeling, 2012

Professional Services

Reviewer for:

- The 31st AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI-17)
- SSCI 16 CCF Big data 16/17 CCPR 16

Teaching Assistant

- Machine Learning (for M.Sc. students), Fall, 2017
- Advanced Language Programme Design (for B.Sc. students), Fall, 2015
- Mathematical Modeling (for B.Sc. students), Spring, 2013

Skills

Proficient at C, Python, MATLAB, LaTeX.